<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Trigger Blog</title>
    <description>Trigger Blog
</description>
    <link>http://blog.triggerapp.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.triggerapp.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2016 16:31:18 +1000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2016 16:31:18 +1000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Recruit Smarter with Trigger</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We’ve spoken about the benefits of of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.triggerapp.com/2015/11/three-cool-things-you-didnt-know-trigger-could-do/&quot;&gt;email to task&lt;/a&gt; feature before, but today I wanted to to draw special attention to how this can be used to make recruiting easier for your team, and how we at Trigger manage this ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We advertise our available roles in a few places but for the purpose of this blog I’m going to discuss Seek only. Seek has a pretty great Employer end which I find especially useful for emailing a large number of candidates a single communication but it’s missing a few key features - we use Trigger to pick up the slack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first step was to create a company in Trigger called “Jobs”, projects are then created for each available position. Back on Seek the listing is set up so that applications are sent direct to the email of the corresponding project. Tasks are automatically created for each application as they come in with any resumes and cover letters attached. As usual the tasks are assigned to the project owner and everyone on the project can view and discuss the application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the things I most like about running our recruitment in this way is how easy it is to collaborate with other stakeholders. If I’m not sure about an applicant I can easily @mention to get another opinion or, should I see an amazing applicant I want to get on to straight away, it’s very easy to grab the attention of those who will be involved in the interview stage, switching the assignee as necessary. With all communication and discussion about the applicant happening within the task it’s very, very easy for anyone who hasn’t been involved from the beginning to quickly catch up on anything of note.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Provided everyone logs their time, running applications in this way also makes it incredibly easy to see how much recruitment actually costs your business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To close out applicants just close out the task as usual - I’m sure it would be nothing but complimentary but if you’re worried about new applicants reading what you’ve said about them just delete that task or project entirely once you’re done :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy hiring!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.triggerapp.com/2016/09/recruit-smarter-with-trigger/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.triggerapp.com/2016/09/recruit-smarter-with-trigger/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Feature Spotlight: The Contractor Role</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We’ve had a tonne of questions about our the Contractor role recently so thought it timely to recap how exactly this role differs from an Employee and how it can be used to its full potential!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aside from Client, the Contractor is the most limited of all the Trigger roles. Generally used for (you guessed it) Contractors, it can be used for any collaborator who is logging time on projects for one of your companies but doesn’t need, or isn’t authorised to view information pertaining to other companies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can invite a contractor through the People tab from wherever you are in the app. Just select + Add in the top right , select Invite Employee, enter the contractor’s email address and select only the companies you wish for them to have access to. Click Invite Employee and an invitation to join you will be sent straight to their inbox.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Much like an Employee, contractors can log time, update and complete tasks. However, unlike the Employee user, they are only able to access projects within companies they are invited to; they can’t see billing rates, fixed fees or time sheets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can add a Contractor to as many or as few companies as you like and remove them at any time. Just select the company you’d like to remove them from, then click the X next to their name. You will need to be either an Admin or Owner to in order to do this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy Contracting!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.triggerapp.com/2016/08/feature-spotlight-the-contractor-role/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.triggerapp.com/2016/08/feature-spotlight-the-contractor-role/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Kanban is Here!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The long awaited Kanban has arrived!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/kanban.png&quot; alt=&quot;kanban board&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Incredibly simple and powerful, the Kanban page displays your tasks as cards placed in columns for each status. Allowing you to visualise your team workflow and become even more efficient.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In case you are not familiar, Kanban is a visualisation tool that enables you to optimise your workflow. It is one of the most (if not the most) used frameworks for those in agile development and has recently gained popularity within media companies, manufacturing and even investment banking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To give it a spin just jump in to the task list for any of your projects and select the Kanban view.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fun Fact: Kanban is literally signboard or billboard in Japanese so saying Kanban Board is kind of like saying ATM Machine&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.triggerapp.com/2016/07/kanban-is-here/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.triggerapp.com/2016/07/kanban-is-here/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Ch-ch-ch-ch-changes</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Just a quick note to let you know that we’ve tweaked a few things in Trigger that we hope will save you those increasingly precious seconds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First up, when entering a new task from the “create new” bar in the task view of a project you no longer need to reach all the way across to your mouse to click the “create” button. You are now able to save these details by pressing ctrl + enter on your keyboard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Secondly, we spoke about our bookmarks feature recently and received some great feedback. In light of this we’ve made the process a little easier. Now once you have saved the name of your bookmark it will appear immediately in your bookmarks lists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, we’ve made a couple of changes to our milestones feature. Milestones now show in the order in which they were created with the newest first and we’ve also introduced a brand new “group by milestone” button. You can find this in the top right of the task view of a project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Team Trigger.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.triggerapp.com/2016/07/ch-ch-ch-ch-changes/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.triggerapp.com/2016/07/ch-ch-ch-ch-changes/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Three cool things you didn’t know Trigger could do</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s come to our attention that some of our users are doing things the long way and aren’t aware of a few features we think are pretty useful. As we are all about productivity we thought we’d send across a few of our favourite time savers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;keyboard-shortcuts&quot;&gt;Keyboard Shortcuts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pressing the ? key while in Trigger will bring up a list of all the keyboard shortcuts available to you. Our favourites are are the t and s shortcuts, t opens up the new task form and s will take you immediately to the search bar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;email-to-tasks&quot;&gt;Email to Tasks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An even quicker way to create new tasks is to forward them to Trigger directly from your email inbox. Each project on Trigger has a unique email address, to find this go to the desired project, select the + symbol in the right hand corner and then choose the “Email Task” option. This will copy the email address to your clipboard. To save having to do this each time we usually save the email address in our contacts with Trigger as the first name and the name of the project as the last name. Simply forward the email to this address and a task will be created automatically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bookmark-searches&quot;&gt;Bookmark Searches&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re finding yourself navigating to a particular page frequently it can be helpful to save this as a bookmark. This can be especially useful for specific search result page. Just visit the page you’d like to bookmark, select the star icon in the top right-hand corner and click “Bookmark this page”. From here you’ll be able to enter a title and save. The bookmark can then be accessed from this same menu.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let us know how you go!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Team Trigger&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.triggerapp.com/2015/11/three-cool-things-you-didnt-know-trigger-could-do/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.triggerapp.com/2015/11/three-cool-things-you-didnt-know-trigger-could-do/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Trigger now has more invoice templates</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We’re happy to announce that Trigger now has more invoice templates!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;basic&quot;&gt;Basic&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/basic.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;basic template&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;standard&quot;&gt;Standard&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/standard.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;standard template&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;modern&quot;&gt;Modern&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/modern.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;modern template&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;clean&quot;&gt;Clean&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/clean.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;clean template&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can choose the one which best matches your visual identity in Account Settings / Invoice Settings / Invoice Template:&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.triggerapp.com/2015/04/trigger-has-now-more-invoice-templates/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.triggerapp.com/2015/04/trigger-has-now-more-invoice-templates/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Feature Update 10 April 2015</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As always we have been hard at work adding new features and improvements to Trigger. Our goal with these changes is to make Trigger easier than ever to use and get your work done!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;schedule&quot;&gt;Schedule&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our new schedule view has received a lot of positive feedback (you can access the view here). On your schedule you can now make changes to days in the past (previously you could only update days in the future).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of our planned features which we hope to release shortly will allow you to have more than one project on each day in your schedule.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;task-pages&quot;&gt;Task Pages&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every task has a description and we had several requests to allow everyone to see when a task description was updated and what changes were made.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now when you update a task description you will see something like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;custom-currency-symbol&quot;&gt;Custom Currency Symbol&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We now allow custom currency symbols to be used in Trigger. You can now enter any character you would like to use for your currency symbol.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;back-to-last-search&quot;&gt;Back to Last Search&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the top of task updates you will now see a “Back to Last Search Button” if you came to that page by a search.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.triggerapp.com/2015/04/feature-update-07-april-2015/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.triggerapp.com/2015/04/feature-update-07-april-2015/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Trigger is now free for 60 days!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We are proud to announce that you can now try Trigger free for 60 days, this is to give you time to really see the power and value of catching all logged time, and billing for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After speaking to agencies and teams that didn’t extend their 14 day trial we realised that they hadn’t seen or used 90% of the powerful timetracking, invoicing and reporting features that set Trigger apart from the ‘task management systems’ out there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trigger guides small businesses and teams, helping them keep the conversation in one place, time logged in context, and then at invoice time getting paid is a breeze.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hope that by giving you 60 days, you’ll have a chance to get addicted to knowing where you’re at with all your projects and being more profitable, and your team the chance to see how Trigger can help you be more productive and get your work done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no credit card required, and you can get &lt;a href=&quot;www.triggerapp.com/signups/new&quot;&gt;get started here!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.triggerapp.com/2014/11/trigger-is-now-free-for-60-days/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.triggerapp.com/2014/11/trigger-is-now-free-for-60-days/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
