<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Trigger Blog</title>
    <description>Trigger Blog
</description>
    <link>http://blog.triggerapp.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.triggerapp.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2017 09:38:38 +0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2017 09:38:38 +0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>13 Reasons why Trigger is the Best Alternative to Basecamp</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In a world where it seems that a new project management app launches every week, Basecamp, started in Chicago, Illinois, way back in 1999, has become one of the grandfather apps in the project management world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basecamp has been around so long that it’s parent company, 37Signals (now renamed Basecamp) has had time to: expand its offering with a CRM (Customer Relationship Management) system called Highrise and a group chat product called Campfire; and then contract its offering again (Highrise has since spun off into its own company and Campfire is now part of Basecamp’s latest iteration, Basecamp 3).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But a lot has changed since 1999. So, if you’re looking for a modern project management app that offers a lot more functionality than Basecamp, you’re in the right place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are 13 reasons why we think &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.triggerapp.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Trigger&lt;/a&gt; is the best project management alternative to Basecamp, to help you better manage your time-conscious projects and budgets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;built-in-time-tracking-including-target-hours-vs-logged-hours&quot;&gt;1. Built-in time tracking (including target hours vs logged hours)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re a savvy business manager, tracking your team’s time can be critical for the success of your service-based business, where you need to know, for sure, how long it takes to complete tasks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unlike Basecamp, you do not need to pay a third party provider for time tracking in Trigger. Our built-in time tracking comes at no extra cost and it can help you stop overservicing clients and start increasing your business’ profitability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ability to see target hours versus logged hours (and not just a dummy bucket of tracked time) is also a godsend to project managers who need to keep projects on time, on track and on budget.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;built-in-management-reporting-on-screen-and-csv-reports&quot;&gt;2. Built-in management reporting (on-screen and CSV reports)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basecamp offers some basic on-screen reports, but Trigger offers much more expansive on-screen and CSV management reporting options for today’s data-driven manager.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Current Trigger reports include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Company, Project, Task, Task Description, Status, Assignee, Due Date, Logged Hours, Total Hours, - Employee, Employee Hours&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tag, Company, Project, Task, Task Description, Status, Assignee, Due Date, Logged Hours, Total Hours&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Company, Project, Task, Billable Status, Logged Hours&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Uninvoiced Companies with Billable items&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Timesheets (by Company, by Date and/or Employee)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Monthly revenue&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Billable hours&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;My hours&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;built-in-invoicing&quot;&gt;3. Built-in invoicing&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trigger has built-in invoicing functionality, but after all these years, Basecamp still does not. We couldn’t even see a third party invoicing integration on Basecamp’s integrations page. This means if you’re using Basecamp and wanting an invoicing solution, you’ll probably need to go hunting for an invoicing app that runs separately (and at an additional cost) to Basecamp.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;xero-integration&quot;&gt;4. Xero integration&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trigger syncs smoothly to the popular accounting application, Xero, which means its perfect for small and medium sized businesses who use Xero.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Connecting Xero with Trigger will allow you to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Import Xero Accounts&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Import Xero Contacts as Companies&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Import Xero Tracking Categories&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Import Xero Currency&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Import Xero Employees&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Import Xero Leave Applications&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sync invoices to Xero&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No Xero account yet? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kqzyfj.com/2p98y1A719PYSZQQWTPRSTYXUVQ&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Try Xero for free&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;slack-integration&quot;&gt;5. Slack integration&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basecamp offers a group chat function, but it’s nowhere near as powerful as what Slack offers, so that’s why, here at Trigger, we integrated with Slack (which is free for 30% of its current user base) rather than spending money on building a new group chat platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;View how our Trigger-to-Slack integration works &lt;a href=&quot;http://productupdates.triggerapp.com/2017/06/new-slack-integration/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;View why we love Slack &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.triggerapp.com/2017/06/7-top-reasons-we-love-slack/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;tasks-list-view-all-of-account-company-or-project&quot;&gt;6. Tasks list view (all of account, company or project)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trigger offers a comprehensive tasks list view (with sophisticated filtering) which displays every task in your account and/or just the tasks for one company or project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is different from Basecamp, which focusses on a per-project view, rather than per-project and per-tasks views.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;advanced-task-management-ordering-and-sorting&quot;&gt;7. Advanced task management, ordering and sorting&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trigger allows you to filter and sort tasks in just as many ways as your business is different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We currently enable you to sort your task by:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;By priority&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;By due date&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;By task number&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;By task name&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;By tag&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;By assignee&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;By author&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;By status&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;By company name&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;By project name&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;By total hours logged&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;kanban-boards&quot;&gt;8. Kanban boards&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you love the visual appeal of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.triggerapp.com/alternative-to-trello&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Trello&lt;/a&gt;-like Kanban boards, you’ll love that, unlike Basecamp, Trigger offers a Kanban board option for your tasks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And unlike competitors &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.triggerapp.com/alternative-to-asana&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;such as Asana&lt;/a&gt;, Trigger doesn’t marry you to one view of the other. Trigger allows you the ability to easily switch between a Tasks list view and a Kanban board view, at any point in time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ability-to-let-clients-in-to-collaborate&quot;&gt;9. Ability to let clients in to collaborate&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trigger allows you to invite clients in to collaborate. It will also allow you to choose to keep private status updates, so you can keep your internal conversations private and only make public the conversations you’re happy for your clients to see and collaborate on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basecamp only offers this in their “Clientside” feature, which is for subscribers on the US$79/month plan and the US$3000/month enterprise plans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;optional-ability-to-show-clients-their-billable-info-target-hours-and-logged-hours&quot;&gt;10. Optional ability to show clients their billable info, target hours and logged hours&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trigger offers the optional ability to show clients their billable information (not your internal costs), target hours and logged hours. Basecamp does not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, if you’re in favour of (optional) total client transparency, Trigger might be perfect for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;calendar&quot;&gt;11. Calendar&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basecamp has a “Schedule” view which shows due dates (which is similar to Trigger’s “Calendar” view). However, unlike Trigger, Basecamp’s Schedule is only inside each project itself, it does not show an all-of-account (or all-per-person) summary of due dates, for easier reference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;team-schedule&quot;&gt;12. Team schedule&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trigger offers an awesome team schedule for team organisation and capacity planning. Basecamp does not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/compare-basecamp/team_schedule.png&quot; alt=&quot;Schedule&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;super-responsiveness&quot;&gt;13. Super-responsiveness&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unlike some of the old names in the project management field, we try to be super responsive to our customer’s changing needs and requests at Trigger. We’re adding customer-requested features and improvements all the time, so if you have an awesome idea for us, don’t hesitate to reach out to us &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:support@triggerapp.com&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/compare-basecamp/compare_table.png&quot; alt=&quot;Compare to Basecamp&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;want-to-make-the-switch-from-basecamp&quot;&gt;Want to make the switch from Basecamp?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re interested in switching from Basecamp to Trigger, you’re in luck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trigger offers a quick Basecamp import integration that allows you to easily:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Import Basecamp Todolists&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Import Basecamp Todos&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Import Basecamp Comments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also offer a quick Highrise integration, to bring across your Highrise companies and users in just a few clicks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Want to try it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.triggerapp.com/users/sign_in&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And welcome to Trigger. :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.triggerapp.com/2017/06/13-reasons-why-trigger-is-the-best-alternative-to-basecamp/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.triggerapp.com/2017/06/13-reasons-why-trigger-is-the-best-alternative-to-basecamp/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Do I Really Need A Time Tracker?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;If you’ve been debating whether or not to start using a time tracker for your business, the answer is yes, if you’re in a service-based business where your projects depend on an hourly input, you do need a time tracker - and you probably already know it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not surprisingly, &lt;a href=&quot;https://hbr.org/2015/01/workers-are-bad-at-filling-out-timesheets-and-it-costs-billions-a-day&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;billions of dollars&lt;/a&gt; are shaved off the economy each year because team members are not tracking their time accurately. It’s easy to do. We’re all busy. We all believe we’re working as hard as we can. We all feel bad when client projects run over time and most of us are too scared to ask our clients to fund our shortfall anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But that’s the beauty of time tracking: the more you track your time, the more you learn what projects are likely to run over budget and the smarter you get about budget estimations for future client jobs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you still need a list of reasons to track time in your business, here are our top three:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;to-stop-losing-money&quot;&gt;1. To stop losing money&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few months ago, we asked our customers why they pay for Trigger as their time tracking and project management solution. The most common response we got was “because, before Trigger, we were losing money by overservicing clients”. So many customers said the same thing that we actually changed the words on our home page to mirror what we were hearing from our customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reality of most small and medium sized businesses is that, if we’re honest with ourselves, we underestimate a lot of client jobs and we end up overservicing clients and losing money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But by the time we realise that, it’s often too late to do anything about it. Contracts are signed and personal relationships are built. To rock the boat and ask clients for more money is always a risky move and most of us choose to wear the loss and hope we’ll get it better next time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But that’s the thing. We can’t just hope we’ll estimate better next time. We need to be accurately time tracking every single task and project so we can learn how to estimate better next time - and the time after that - and that time after that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;to-see-whats-really-going-on-in-your-business&quot;&gt;2. To see what’s really going on in your business&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s say you have a senior team member named Jennifer. She’s an awesome asset for your team and delivers exceptional work, every time. But the problem is that it always takes Jennifer longer to complete projects and tasks than you would expect, and you don’t know why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By enabling Jennifer to track her time, you and Jennifer will start to learn what tasks are taking her the most time and what tasks she could potentially delegate to another team member - or to a cheaper, external resource.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, if Jennifer is spending 10 hours doing online research that a freelancer could do for half the price, a time tracking app can help you identify this and take action early, before Jennifer becomes overwhelmed and runs behind deadline on the work where her expertise is needed more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may think “well, it’s only 10 hours we’re talking about”. But every “only 10 hours” adds up and that’s exactly the kind of trend that a report from a clever time tracking tool like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.triggerapp.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Trigger&lt;/a&gt; can help you identify and rectify asap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or let’s say that you are Jennifer…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You know that you are given 101 things to do for each project but when you ask for more resources, in the heat of the meeting, you find it hard to quantify exactly how much time you spend on what and it’s frustrating to not be able to articulate what’s really going in on your work desk - because you haven’t been accurately tracking it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re Jennifer, a time tracker could genuinely relieve some of your pain because when you (and your manager) run reports on how long it takes to perform certain tasks, it will be much easier to say, “See, those client liaison calls are eating so much into my work time that it’s impossible for me to get everything done on time, unless I get some help with either the client calls or with some of my other tasks.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;to-boost-team-performance&quot;&gt;3.  To boost team performance&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even for high performers, there’s nothing like vanity metrics to encourage team members to work at their highest capacity. Before &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.triggerapp.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Trigger&lt;/a&gt;, I confess that I’d never used a time tracker. I’d always been a high performer, so I thought the concept was irrelevant for me. How wrong I was. Now that I use Trigger to track time on my work tasks, I’ll often work extra time before logging off at the end of the day, because I hate seeing a low hours count on my profile and I always want to feel better about my data count.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s another example of the power of vanity metrics…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some time ago, I watched a video of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6fQHLK1aIBs&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;lecture 14&lt;/a&gt; in Sam Altman’s &lt;em&gt;How To Start A Startup&lt;/em&gt; series at Stanford University, where Keith Rabois (a former exec at PayPal, Slide, Square and LinkedIn) told a vanity metrics story. He said that when he was at LinkedIn, the personal profile button was not easy to find on the LinkedIn home page. Yet, despite that, 25% of clicks from the home page every day were to a user’s personal profile, because people love looking at and improving their data!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;want-to-start-tracking-your-time&quot;&gt;Want to start tracking your time?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trigger is one of many low cost, cloud-based solutions that can help you track time and help stop your company losing money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What makes us different from our competitors?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trigger integrates time tracking with project management. This means that time is not logged in dummy time buckets - instead, time is always logged against a real task, project and company, which makes it easier to manage your projects and know what’s really going on in your business.
So, if know you need a time tracker and you want to help your business stop overservicing clients, why not &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.triggerapp.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;try Trigger today&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;30-day free trial. No contracts. No credit card required.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And we’re really nice people too!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.triggerapp.com/2017/06/00-do-i-really-need-a-time-tracker/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.triggerapp.com/2017/06/00-do-i-really-need-a-time-tracker/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>9 Reasons why Trigger is the Best Alternative to Trello</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Making headlines earlier this year when it was &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Trello&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;sold for $425 million&lt;/a&gt;, the project management app Trello is, and will always be, a force to be reckoned with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But whilst you can run work projects on Trello - the unofficial king of Kanban boards, is it really the best product for agencies and consultancies with more than a few team members and projects?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We think not. Here are ten reasons why we think &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.triggerapp.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Trigger&lt;/a&gt; (built locally here in Brisbane, and integrated with Slack, just like Trello) is the best alternative to Trello (built 15,520km away by Fog Creek Software in New York).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;better-for-managing-multiple-large-projects&quot;&gt;1. Better for managing multiple large projects&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trello can be a great starter tool for small teams with a limited number of projects. But if you Google “what do people dislike about Trello?” you’ll find the common consensus is that it’s easy to outgrow Trello. At the point when you want need the ability to better manage multiple large projects, we propose that Trigger is your best alternative to Trello.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is because Trigger offers much more than Trello’s famous boards and cards: Trigger is a full-blown project management solution with time tracking against tasks, easy internal and external collaboration, built-in reporting, built-in invoicing and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ability-to-easily-switch-between-kanban-and-task-list-views-for-every-project&quot;&gt;2. Ability to easily switch between Kanban and task list views for every project&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The beauty of Trigger’s Kanban boards is that you can easily switch between each project’s Kanban and task list views at any time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whereas Trello only allows you to have Kanban boards or…. you guessed it… Kanban boards. This makes Trello even less flexible than another heavyweight in the project management space: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.triggerapp.com/alternative-to-asana&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Asana&lt;/a&gt;. Asana has no way for you to easily switch between the two views (you must nominate one view only at the time you set up a project), but at least Asana gives you two views.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;built-in-reporting-on-screen-and-csv-reports&quot;&gt;3. Built-in reporting (on-screen and CSV reports)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trello offers CSV reporting on a project basis, but as one of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.quora.com/What-do-people-dislike-about-Trello&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;critics on Quora&lt;/a&gt; says, Trello has a “lack of detailed reporting without adding multiple Gmail extensions”. This is not an ideal solution, because not only do you potentially have to pay for extensions and/or Power-ups, another critic noted that “the problem with integrations is that they can never be completely seamless”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trigger offers expansive on-screen and CSV report options and very soon we’ll be launching a dedicated Reports tab that will offer even more insights to help you know exactly what’s going on in your business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Current management reports in Trigger include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Company, Project, Task, Task Description, Status, Assignee, Due Date, Logged Hours, Total Hours, Employee, Employee Hours&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tag, Company, Project, Task, Task Description, Status, Assignee, Due Date, Logged Hours, Total Hours&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Company, Project, Task, Billable Status, Logged Hours&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Uninvoiced Companies with Billable items&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Timesheets (by Company, by Date and/or Employee)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Monthly revenue&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Billable hours&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;My hours&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;built-in-time-tracking-including-target-hours-vs-logged-hours&quot;&gt;4. Built-in time tracking (including target hours vs logged hours)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a business owner or project manager, time tracking can genuinely mean the difference between losing money, breaking even or making a profit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, if you run a service-based business and you want to accurately track how long it takes to complete tasks, Trigger’s built-in time tracking could be a life-changer because it can help you stop overservicing clients and start increasing your business’ profitability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;built-in-invoicing-including-xero-integration&quot;&gt;5. Built-in invoicing (including Xero integration)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trigger has built-in invoicing functionality, because it’s been designed from the outset as an all-in-one project management solution. Trello does not have built-in invoicing and when we looked for an add-on in the Trello Power Ups section, we could not even find a dedicated invoicing add-on for Trello.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And if you use &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kqzyfj.com/2p98y1A719PYSZQQWTPRSTYXUVQ&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Xero&lt;/a&gt; for your invoices, you can sync Trigger with Xero and never have to double-handle an invoice again!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;private-status-updates-to-give-you-confidence-to-invite-clients-in&quot;&gt;6. Private status updates (to give you confidence to invite clients in)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trello doesn’t allow private status updates, which might explain why some Trigger customers have told us that they were always nervous about inviting clients into Trello (before they swapped over to using Trigger).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trigger definitely gives you the ability to make private status updates, so your internal conversations stay private and only the conversations you’re happy for your clients to see (and collaborate on) are made public.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;optional-ability-to-show-clients-their-billable-info-target-hours-and-logged-hours&quot;&gt;7. Optional ability to show clients their billable info, target hours and logged hours&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want greater transparency for your clients, you’ll love Trigger’s (optional) ability for you to show your clients their billable information (not your internal costs, by the way), target hours and logged hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was a feature requested by one of our customers in Spain who has more than 60 clients using the Trigger platform - for free!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;real-time-feed-of-all-project-activity&quot;&gt;8. Real-time feed of all project activity&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want the ability to run your eyes down a real-time feed of all activity on your account each day, Trello can’t help you as well as Trigger can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trello can offer a Kanban board view of project activity, but Trigger gives a real time feed of all company, project and task entries and status updates. This is in addition to our email notifications for updates and @mentions (set at your frequency preferences), as well as our in-app notifications for @mentions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;responsiveness-to-customer-requests&quot;&gt;9. Responsiveness to customer requests&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unlike some of the big names in the project management field, at Trigger we try to be super responsive to our customer’s changing needs and requests. We’re adding customer-requested features and improvements all the time, so if you have an awesome idea for us, don’t hesitate to reach out to us &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:support@triggerapp.com&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/compare-trello/compare_table.png&quot; alt=&quot;Trigger vs. Trello&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.triggerapp.com/users/sign_in&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Try Trigger for yourself today!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.triggerapp.com/2017/06/9-reasons-why-trigger-is-the-best-alternative-to-trello/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.triggerapp.com/2017/06/9-reasons-why-trigger-is-the-best-alternative-to-trello/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>7 Top Reasons We Love Slack</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;You know how, every now and then, you discover a workplace productivity app that actually does what it promises and makes life easier?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, we did and it’s called &lt;a href=&quot;https://slack.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Slack&lt;/a&gt;. And that’s why, alongside our favourite project management app, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.triggerapp.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Trigger&lt;/a&gt;, Slack is our favourite tool in the office and we’d all be genuinely lost without it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-slack&quot;&gt;What is Slack?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Slack is a real-time, cloud-based, messaging and collaboration platform. It was founded by Stewart Butterfield in August 2013 to use in his computer game company at the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A short three and half years later, &lt;a href=&quot;http://fortune.com/2016/04/01/slack-raises-200-million-at-3-8-billion-valuation/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Fortune reported&lt;/a&gt; in April 2016 that Slack had grown to an incredible value of $3.8 billion, with a daily user base of 2.7 million fans. Slack’s crazy growth curve confirms that we are not the only team that loves this brilliant productivity tool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/9RJZMSsH7-g&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-the-name-slack&quot;&gt;Why the name Slack?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Slack_(software)&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;According to Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;, the name Slack is an acronym for “Searchable Log of All Conversation and Knowledge”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-much-does-slack-cost&quot;&gt;How much does Slack cost?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Slack has both free and paid options. According to Fortune, approximately 30 percent of Slack’s user base don’t pay a cent. This is understandable, considering that for free, you can have (almost) unlimited users per channel and you can search up to 10,000 of your team’s messages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-do-we-love-slack&quot;&gt;Why do we love Slack?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;we-get-instant-answers&quot;&gt;1. We get instant answers&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Waiting for your colleague to sift through their emails and decide which emails are a priority to answer can be both ineffective and frustrating for the whole team, especially when you have very quick questions that can be solved with very quick answers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Slack’s real-time messaging is therefore particularly perfect for: instant Q&amp;amp;A: quickly seeking an opinion or approval; and/or updating the team with quick messages of all shapes and sizes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example:
“Jen, did you get approval for us to start work on Client ABC’s social media?”
“Team: Coffee machine repair guy coming at noon”
“Jack, want a red or orange button on our new home page?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are quick questions or updates that don’t need emails or someone to get up from their desk and walk downstairs to ask a colleague for an answer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you facilitate a culture of speed, that’s exactly what you’ll get. So if it’s something quick, we use Slack. For everything else (especially client related), we use Trigger. Together, this means that unlike other businesses, we very rarely experience internal email overwhelm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;we-see-what-we-want-to-see&quot;&gt;2. We see what we want to see&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Slack gives you three main options for messaging: direct messages; group channels; and private channels. This is hugely beneficial to our workflow because it means that everyone only receives (and/or can choose to read) only the messages that affect them directly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s an example of a private channel. In our case, we have remote workers who really don’t care if the coffee machine is broken today or if we need a volunteer to lock up the office tomorrow. So, private channels are a godsend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/slack/slack-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;Slack&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s an example of some of our public (opt-in) channels in our Trigger team. As with any channel, it’s label changes to a bold white if there are new messages in there to read. (You also have the option for desktop and/or mobile push notifications.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/slack/slack-2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Slack&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And here’s an example of the direct messaging channel. Anyone who you have directly messaged recently will show up in that list for easy access.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/slack/slack-3.png&quot; alt=&quot;Slack&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;we-know-our-teams-movements&quot;&gt;3. We know our team’s movements&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most teams these days are not confined to the same four walls, 9am-5pm. Team members are working flexible hours, travelling interstate or abroad, out and about for meetings, or needing to close the office door to block out the world and get stuff done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a result, keeping track of everyone’s movements and knowing who (and when) are best to message or call, can be tricky - even if you have your Trigger and Google calendars synced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With Slack, you can see who’s online (green circle), who’s offline (empty circle), who’s online but has their notifications switched to snooze mode (green circle with “Z”) and who’s both offline and switched to snooze mode (empty circle with “Z”).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also set icons next to your name for when you are “working remotely”, “in a meeting”, “commuting”, “out sick”, “vacationing”,  and well, anything you’d like because you can customise the icons and messages however you choose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whilst this might sound more fun that practical, these features in Slack are actually extremely useful for knowing who might reply quickly, who will be back online soon and who you might need to pick up the phone and call directly if you need a quick answer to an urgent request.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/slack/slack-4.png&quot; alt=&quot;Slack&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;we-are-kept-in-the-loop&quot;&gt;4. We are kept in the loop&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://api.slack.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Slack has an API&lt;/a&gt; that allows you to integrate many of your favourite applications (to receive their notifications in your Slack channels), including Trigger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, we use &lt;a href=&quot;http://intercom.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Intercom&lt;/a&gt; for our customer service and we’ve set up Slack to integrate with Intercom. When we get a new message in Intercom, it feeds directly into our Slack notification (and on-screen notifications).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s how the Intercom message feed looks in our Slack #customer-support channel:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/slack/slack-5.png&quot; alt=&quot;Slack&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have similar integrations set up with GitHub and Bugsnag (for our development work).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s how a GitHub message feed looks in our Slack #development channel:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/slack/slack-6.png&quot; alt=&quot;Slack&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And of course, we have a Slack integration with Trigger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s how one of our Trigger notifications looks in our nominated Slack channel (and yes, you can set your Trigger notifications up for different projects to feed into different Slack channels):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/slack/slack-7.png&quot; alt=&quot;Slack&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even if you turn your desktop notifications off, the benefit of these Slack feeds for team members and managers is that, at any given time, you can run your eyes down your team’s Slack feeds and get a quick and insightful overview of everything that’s been going on in team conversations and client projects, on any given day of your choosing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;we-can-upload-files-easier-than-in-google-docs&quot;&gt;5. We can upload files easier than in Google Docs&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Slack lets you attach, drag and drop documents, screenshots, PDFs, images, animated gifs and videos directly into conversations, from your computer, Google Drive and Dropbox.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, if you’re adding a file to a group channel, everyone can easily access the file and you don’t need to clog up emails, worry about forgetting to add someone, or waste time creating the email and adding everyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plus, you can upload multiple files and images at once. Sounds basic, but we’re forever frustrated that Google only allows you to upload one image at time in a Google Doc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Uploading files to Slack is so much easier than uploading files to Google Docs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/slack/slack-8.png&quot; alt=&quot;Slack&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;we-can-search-conversations&quot;&gt;6. We can search conversations&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Slack has a user-friendly search box that makes it very easy to type in any term you’re looking for and get results displayed instantly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This comes in very handy when we forget to copy/paste or screenshot a conversation or approval over to our relevant Trigger task for project management and record-keeping.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/slack/slack-9.png&quot; alt=&quot;Slack&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;we-love-how-slack-oozes-happy&quot;&gt;7. We love how Slack oozes happy&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you log in to Slack, you are greeted with a (semi) random message that makes you feel loved. Who doesn’t enjoy a (semi) personal, happy message to start their day?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/slack/slack-10.png&quot; alt=&quot;Slack&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/slack/slack-11.png&quot; alt=&quot;Slack&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/slack/slack-12.png&quot; alt=&quot;Slack&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/slack/slack-13.png&quot; alt=&quot;Slack&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;trigger-to-slack-integration&quot;&gt;Trigger-to-Slack Integration&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, if your team is overwhelmed with email and meetings that drag on for too long, maybe try Slack. It’s an integral part of our productivity workflow and we recommend it 100 percent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re already using Trigger as your time tracking and project management solution, you can set up your Trigger-to-Slack integration &lt;a href=&quot;https://triggerapp.com/integrations&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re not in our Trigger community yet, we invite you to try our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.triggerapp.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;30-day free trial here&lt;/a&gt; (no credit card required).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the SlackBot says…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We like you”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, see you inside &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.triggerapp.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Trigger&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.triggerapp.com/2017/06/7-top-reasons-we-love-slack/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.triggerapp.com/2017/06/7-top-reasons-we-love-slack/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>7 Reasons why Trigger is the Best Alternative to WorkflowMax</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Xero_(software)&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Purchased by Xero in 2012 for NZ$6 million&lt;/a&gt;, WorkflowMax is another project management app often compared to Trigger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can understand why: both Trigger and WorkflowMax combine time tracking with project management and invoicing (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.xero.com/au/pricing/?CJAID=12387450&amp;amp;CJPID=8290063&amp;amp;utm_source=Affiliate&amp;amp;utm_medium=Text&amp;amp;utm_campaign=PPP&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;direct to Xero&lt;/a&gt;), so on the surface, they have a lot of similarities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But once you get past the Xero copy-cat screens, you’ll soon realise why we think &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.triggerapp.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Trigger&lt;/a&gt; (homegrown in Brisbane, Australia) is the best alternative to WorkflowMax (headquartered in Wellington, New Zealand).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;modern-uiux-design&quot;&gt;1. Modern UI/UX design&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of Trigger’s strengths is its modern user interface (UI) and user experience (UX). WorkflowMax’s old style interface might be acceptable for tradies or accountants who potentially don’t need to prioritise design, but it’s not the best option for creative agencies and marketing consultancies who want to invite their clients into their project management platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A quick search on Google shows we’re not alone in our thinking:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We think WorkflowMax is brilliant for construction, manufacturing and trades related businesses…” says an accounting firm &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mintaccounting.co.uk/blog/post/2042/Mint-Love-Workflow-Max/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;source&lt;/a&gt; who conveniently omitted any recommendation for other specific industries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.merchantmaverick.com/reviews/workflowmax-review-2017/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;source&lt;/a&gt; said,  “…the UI is one of WorkflowMax’s least effective tricks. I wouldn’t call it ugly, exactly, but it is a far cry from systems like [insert competitor names - Ed.], whose interfaces are a joy to work with. Operations in WorkflowMax seem to require more clicking/searching/window opening than would be ideal.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;kanban-boards-including-an-ability-to-easily-switch-between-kanban-and-list-views&quot;&gt;2. Kanban boards (including an ability to easily switch between Kanban and list views)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trigger offers Kanban boards, whereas WorkflowMax does not. But on top of that, Trigger offers the ability to easily switch between Kanban and Task List views for a project at any time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This also makes Trigger a better &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.triggerapp.com/alternative-to-trello&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;alternative to Trello&lt;/a&gt; (which only offers Kanban boards), as well as a better &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.triggerapp.com/alternative-to-asana&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;alternative to Asana&lt;/a&gt; (which offers both Kanban and list views, but makes you choose one view only at the time you create a project).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;better-ability-to-manage-your-email-notifications&quot;&gt;3. Better ability to manage your email notifications&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In WorkflowMax, you can only select “on” or “off” for your email notifications. This is not very flexible because in a large team, “all” could mean 100’s of notifications each day/week and “off” could mean you are not kept updated at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Trigger, we give you lots of options. You can set your email notifications to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Real time updates&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Group updates every five minutes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Daily updates&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;No updates (unless you are @mentioned, so you don’t miss something important)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;optional-ability-to-show-clients-their-billable-info-target-hours-and-logged-hours&quot;&gt;4. Optional ability to show clients their billable info, target hours and logged hours&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to a great suggestion by some of our customers, we recently added the optional ability to show clients their billable information (ie. the amounts they are billed, not an internal employee cost), target hours and logged hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This adds a whole new level of transparency for modern agencies and consultancies who wish to share and collaborate openly with their clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;free-timer-app&quot;&gt;5. Free timer app&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’d like the ability to track time without needing to open the Trigger or WorkflowMax applications, you’ll need a timer app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;WorkflowMax currently offers the ability for you to pay one of six external vendors (Actual, Eon, Adobe time Tracking widget, Timeslice, Prod Timer and Time Doctor) and then integrate your timer app with WorkflowMax.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trigger, on the other hand, is launching a 100% free timer app in mid 2017 (so you do not have to pay an external vendor for the privilege of tracking your time in what is already a time tracking application).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;built-in-reporting&quot;&gt;6. Built-in reporting&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both Trigger and WorkflowMax offer various management reports (including CSV reports). We think our reports are more useful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Current Trigger reports include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Company, Project, Task, Task Description, Status, Assignee, Due Date, Logged Hours, Total Hours, Employee, Employee Hours&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tag, Company, Project, Task, Task Description, Status, Assignee, Due Date, Logged Hours, Total Hours&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Company, Project, Task, Billable Status, Logged Hours&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Uninvoiced Companies with Billable items&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Timesheets (by Company, by Date and/or Employee)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Monthly revenue&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Billable hours&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;My hours&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ll also be launching a new Reports tab for our Trigger customers in June/July 2017 with even more insights to help business owners know what’s really going on in their business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ability-to-adapt-quickly-to-your-requests&quot;&gt;7. Ability to adapt quickly to your requests&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unlike some of the big guns in the time tracking and project management industry, we move fast at Trigger and can quickly adapt to your requests. We’re adding customer-requested features and improvements all the time, so if you have a great idea, get in touch &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:support@triggerapp.com&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/compare-workflow-max/compare_table.png&quot; alt=&quot;Trigger vs. WorkflowMax&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;want-to-try-trigger&quot;&gt;Want to try Trigger?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t just take our word for whether Trigger is the best alternative to WorkflowMax.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.triggerapp.com/users/sign_in&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Try Trigger for yourself today!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2017 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.triggerapp.com/2017/05/7-reasons-why-trigger-is-the-best-alternative-to-workflowmax/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.triggerapp.com/2017/05/7-reasons-why-trigger-is-the-best-alternative-to-workflowmax/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>6 Dilbert Videos That Prove You Need Time Tracking</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Did you know that “&lt;a href=&quot;https://hbr.org/2015/01/workers-are-bad-at-filling-out-timesheets-and-it-costs-billions-a-day&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;workers are bad at filling out timesheets and it costs billions a day&lt;/a&gt;”?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yep, that’s what the Harvard Business Review asked in 2015, when they reported on the results of a 500-worker study and subsequent White Paper, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.accelo.com/assets/Uploads/WhitePaperTimeIsMoney.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Time is Money&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The study found that “almost 40% of respondents reported never tracking time spent reading and answering email”. For a service-based business, you can imagine that this starts to add up when an employer bills purely based on timesheets and their entire business profitability depends on efficient timesheet tracking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think your agency or consultancy is too small to warrant a time tracker solution?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think again. It doesn’t matter if you’re large or small: if you’re overservicing clients and losing money, wouldn’t you rather discover this sooner rather than later?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you need more convincing, here are six Dilbert videos by the legendary Scott Adams to help prove why your business needs time tracking:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dilbert-test-results&quot;&gt;1. Dilbert: Test results&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your business depends on client billing, a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.triggerapp.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;reliable time tracking system such as Trigger&lt;/a&gt; is essential for team members to accurately record the time they spend on every task for every client.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don’t provide your team with an easy-to-use tool to track their time, they’re unlikely to track their time accurately and will feel forced to forge their time results - which is potentially worse than not tracking time in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/YgR2lUeEKxk&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dilbert-hallucinated-assumptions&quot;&gt;2. Dilbert: Hallucinated assumptions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’re unlikely to ever get an accurate estimation for how much money it costs for your business to complete a task or project, if your business doesn’t encourage team members to track time - and track time accurately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This means that your client estimations will nearly always be wrong, which effectively renders your client estimations (and claims of client transparency) useless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/NajpgzHHDpE&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dilbert-brilliant-suggestion&quot;&gt;3. Dilbert: Brilliant suggestion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A time tracker can keep everyone in the team accountable. The idea of time tracking might sound counter-intuitive to team harmony, but it’s actually the opposite. Most team members appreciate the ability to track time and be recognised for their efforts. Plus, nothing breaks team harmony than when a sneaky team member reports they did more on a project than they actually did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A time tracking tool encourages honesty within the team and saves timesheets from inexplicable bloat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/8ywkmdiZGxY&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dilbert-best-use-of-time&quot;&gt;4. Dilbert: Best use of time&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just because someone is typing at their laptop furiously, doesn’t mean they’re being productive and/or working on the team’s most urgent priorities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time tracking against real tasks (not purely time tracking into a dummy time bucket, like some of Trigger’s competitors) helps to encourage team members to devote their hours to the best use of time possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/4AZ2DmcBmck&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dilbert-time-management&quot;&gt;5. Dilbert: Time management&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once your team starts to track their time, it’s easier for all of you to see (and monitor) what (and who) is wasting their time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you having too many brainstorming meetings?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you meeting in person when you could be communicating more quickly on Slack or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.triggerapp.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Trigger&lt;/a&gt; instead?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you sending a task to multiple people for review, when in reality, you only need one person to review and approve your work?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/SJoeY3WeSug&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dilbert-random-reorganisation&quot;&gt;6. Dilbert: Random reorganisation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, if you’re not tracking time, you run the risk of guesstimating why things are not working in your business and then reorganising for the sake of reorganising - which is never a smart way to grow and scale a business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/GE1Lm-K6tOM&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;want-more-dilbert&quot;&gt;Want more Dilbert?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you enjoyed these Dilbert videos, head over to our first instalment, &lt;a href=&quot;/2017/04/07-dilbert-videos-that-prove-you-need-project-management/&quot;&gt;7 Dilbert Videos that Prove You Need Project Management&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you still find yourself craving more, there’s a treasure trove of Dilbert workplace videos on the Dilbert YouTube channel &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/user/dilbert/videos&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2017 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.triggerapp.com/2017/05/6-dilbert-videos-that-prove-you-need-time-tracking/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.triggerapp.com/2017/05/6-dilbert-videos-that-prove-you-need-time-tracking/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>10 Reasons why Trigger is the Best Alternative to Asana</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;With &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/asana#/entity&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;US$88.3 million&lt;/a&gt; in funding from some of Silicon Valley’s most high profile investors, Asana is undeniably one of the biggest guns of the project management world. But with so many customer needs and nuances, it’s hard for Asana to be the best project management solution for everyone. What works for Asana’s billion-dollar American customers such as Airbnb, Uber and Pinterest, might not work for small creative agencies in Canada, medium-sized marketing consultancies in Spain or one-person PR agencies in the United Kingdom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re looking for a project management app that helps you better manage your projects and stop overservicing your customers, you’ve landed in the right place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are ten reasons why we think &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.triggerapp.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Trigger&lt;/a&gt; (homegrown in Brisbane, Australia) is the best alternative to Asana (headquartered in San Francisco, United States).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;built-in-time-tracking&quot;&gt;1. Built-in time tracking&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Project management only takes you so far. It’s time-tracking against project tasks that shows a business owner (or project manager) exactly what’s going on in the business and how much time it really takes to service each client.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is important because, too often, small and medium sized agencies and consultancies are too “nice” and end up overservicing clients because they’re not accurately tracking how much time it takes to complete actual tasks. Sound familiar?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a business owner or project manager, time tracking can mean the difference between losing money, breaking even or making a profit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trigger has always had built-in time tracking. Asana hasn’t, so Asana announced a partnership with Harvest a few years ago, where you can add a Harvest timer into your Asana task panel to track time against Asana tasks. The downside of this arrangement is that you’ll need to pay for two services (Asana plus Harvest) rather than one service (Trigger).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;built-in-invoicing&quot;&gt;2. Built-in invoicing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trigger has built-in invoicing functionality, because we think it’s logical that you create your client invoices where all of your client tasks and timesheets are managed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Asana, on the other hand, does not have in-built invoicing. To counter this, you’ll likely need to pay for an add-on service to Asana (that either integrates with Asana or connects via Zapier).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ability-to-easily-switch-between-kanban-and-task-list-views-for-every-project&quot;&gt;3. Ability to easily switch between Kanban and Task List views for every project&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both Trigger and Asana offer Kanban views.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The difference between the two solutions however is that in Trigger, you can easily switch between Kanban and Task List views for a project at any time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whereas with Asana, you must choose if you want the Kanban or Task List view at the time you create the project. Then forever after, you are only able to be see that specific project in that one specific view type.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;better-ability-to-manage-your-email-notifications&quot;&gt;4. Better ability to manage your email notifications&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One complaint about Asana is their &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.brainstormforce.com/asana-at-brainstorm-10-things-we-love-and-5-things-we-hate/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;overload of email notifications&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Asana, you can set your email notifications to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Task reminders&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;All activity&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Weekly dashboard&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Snooze for 1 hour at a time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Trigger, you can set your email notifications to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Real time updates&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Group updates every five minutes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Daily updates&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;No updates (unless you are @mentioned, so you don’t miss something important)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Trigger, you also have greater control over email notifications because you can better specify user roles - and therefore who needs to receive each email notification.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ability-to-specify-user-roles-per-task&quot;&gt;5. Ability to specify user roles per task&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Although Asana allows to keep tasks public or private, it does not let you set user roles within a team or an organization on the whole.” &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.brainstormforce.com/asana-at-brainstorm-10-things-we-love-and-5-things-we-hate/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Trigger, you have a project owner (who you can change at any time), an assignee for each task (who you can also change at any time) and watchers to a task (which you can add or remove at any time, depending on the stage of the task and who you would like to remain involved in that specific task).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This means that in Trigger, the ability to specify user roles per task also gives you greater control over who receives email notifications and updates to tasks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;optional-ability-to-show-clients-their-billable-info-target-hours-and-logged-hours&quot;&gt;6. Optional ability to show clients their billable info, target hours and logged hours&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to a great suggestion by some of our customers, we recently added the optional ability to show clients their billable information, target hours and logged hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Customers who opt for this greater transparency can either choose ‘all clients’ or they can choose which specific clients they would like to be able to see this extra information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note: Billable information is only the amounts that our customers bill to their clients. It is not internal employee salary information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;xero-integration&quot;&gt;7. Xero integration&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unlike Asana, Trigger talks nicely to Xero, so your time tracking meets your invoicing in one click - and you never have to double-handle an invoice again!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No Xero account yet? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kqzyfj.com/2p98y1A719PYSZQQWTPRSTYXUVQ&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Try Xero for free&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;basecamp-integration&quot;&gt;8. Basecamp integration&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unlike Asana, Trigger integrates with Basecamp, so you can quickly import your Basecamp to-do lists, to-dos and comments and make your transition from Basecamp as painless as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bugsnag-integration&quot;&gt;9. Bugsnag integration&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For our software developer customers, Trigger (unlike Asana) also integrates with Bugsnag. This means that issues found in Bugsnag are automatically added as tasks in Trigger, so important software issues never slip through the cracks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See more integrations &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.triggerapp.com/integrations-all&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ability-to-adapt-quickly-to-customer-requests&quot;&gt;10. Ability to adapt quickly to customer requests&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unlike some of the giants in the project management industry, our lean structure at Trigger enables us to be incredibly agile so we can adapt quickly to customer requests. We’re adding customer-requested features and improvements all the time, so please don’t be shy. If have a good idea and you think we should so something about it, we’d love to hear from you &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:support@triggerapp.com&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/compare-asana/compare_table.png&quot; alt=&quot;Trigger vs. Asana&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.triggerapp.com/2017/04/10-reasons-why-trigger-is-the-best-alternative-to-asana/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.triggerapp.com/2017/04/10-reasons-why-trigger-is-the-best-alternative-to-asana/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Has your business lost its Mojo?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Mojo is a fickle thing. Some days your business has that magnetic charm that draws people in, yet other days you feel your business has lost its way when it repels the very customers you’re trying to attract.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hey, don’t beat yourself up about it. Even Austin Powers, the king of mojo, has had his Mojo stolen and had to work hard to steal it back. Business is a rollercoaster of wins and losses and if you don’t get thrown out on the ride, there are bound to be days when you get sick of waiting in the queue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key is to recognise when your business has been missing its Mojo for weeks on end and then committing to do something about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-exactly-is-mojo&quot;&gt;What exactly is Mojo?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gary Bertwistle, in his 2007 book &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Who-Stole-My-Mojo-Better/dp/1741755336/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Who Stole My Mojo?&lt;/a&gt; , Bertwistle calls Mojo “the extra spark that is the difference between having a good day and having a great day. It’s the difference between getting good results and outstanding results”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bertwistle says that “once you get your Mojo working and put that vitality and vigour back into your [business], the rewards come tenfold”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hero/mojo-thumb.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Mojo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-can-you-tell-if-your-business-has-lost-its-mojo&quot;&gt;How can you tell if your business has lost its Mojo?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;John Knight, Managing Director of Queensland’s business advisory firm &lt;a href=&quot;http://businessdepot.com.au/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;businessDEPOT&lt;/a&gt; is fascinated by business Mojo. He and  his 30-plus-member team have advised hundreds of businesses that have lost their Mojo and want advice on how to get it back again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Constantly declining sales and profits, decreased staff motivation and attendance, increased staff and customer turnover, plus a lack of new ideas being put forward by both staff and management” - these are all important signs of a business losing its Mojo, says Knight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other signs include: customer feedback is being ignored and not actioned; team members are tired, overworked and overwhelmed; management feels bored and uninspired; and/or there is an unusual amount of tension in the team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-can-your-business-get-its-mojo-back&quot;&gt;How can your business get its Mojo back?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;go-back-to-your-why&quot;&gt;1. Go back to your ‘why’&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s easy to get lost along the way. So, take yourself back to your reason for going into your business in the first place. Stop. Rethink. Refresh. Then come back and re-strategise. If you don’t have a ‘why’, take time out and find one that matters to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sunshinecoastfashionfestival.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Sunshine Coast Fashion Festival&lt;/a&gt; entrepreneur Jacinta Richmond had been running her annual event for nine years when she lost her Mojo. After much brainstorming, she realised that she had the wrong ‘why’, which was causing her to struggle when she hit bumps in the road. On the verge of closing the festival for good, Richmond’s new ‘why’ has brought her back in 2017 with a renewed vigour and an excitement about her festival’s 10th anniversary this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;decide-if-the-problem-is-you&quot;&gt;2. Decide if the problem is you&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, the business hasn’t lost its mojo, it’s you who’ve lost your mojo and because your business is your life, it’s hard to make that separation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;identify-exactly-where-your-problems-are-coming-from&quot;&gt;3. Identify exactly where your problems are coming from&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Knight references the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pareto_principle&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Pareto principle&lt;/a&gt; when he explains that 80 percent of the problems may come from 20 percent of the product lines, 20 percent of the team members or 20 percent of the customers. He urges business owners to find out which part of the business is broken and needs fixing, before they overhaul the whole business or worse still, rush to sell it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, at Trigger, we regularly hear customer testimonials for our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.triggerapp.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;time tracking&lt;/a&gt; solution such as this one from Dan Clowes from &lt;a href=&quot;http://litoria.com.au/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Litoria Consulting&lt;/a&gt; in Brisbane: “Trigger has been a life-changer. It has made our business so much more efficient and really helped us go from break-even to profitable”. So, sometimes all it takes is a clever tool in your business to help you find what’s broken, fix it and bring your Mojo back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ask-for-help&quot;&gt;4. Ask for help&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Too many business owners carry the weight of the world on their shoulders. Most times, people like to help. It makes them feel valued. In fact, a &lt;a href=&quot;http://digitalcommons.ilr.cornell.edu/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2092&amp;amp;context=articles&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;series of studies&lt;/a&gt; found that people underestimated the likelihood that others would agree to a direct request for help by as much as 50 percent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don’t have a team to help, consider tapping into the wisdom of a business advisor or mentor. For example, sites like Knight’s can offer a marketplace of trusted providers to help. Or if you want some instant advice, try sites like &lt;a href=&quot;https://clarity.fm/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Clarity&lt;/a&gt; to tap into the wisdom of mentors all over the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;stop-doing-a-task-you-dont-need-to-do-anymore&quot;&gt;5. Stop doing a task you don’t need to do anymore&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ask each team member to identify one task that they hate doing that they might not need to be do anymore - either if management requirements are updated and/or if there is an online tool out there to help automate the task. Alleviating just one headache from each person’s desk could in essence relieve one big headache for the whole business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;do-something-that-makes-your-team-smile&quot;&gt;6. Do something that makes your team smile&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Knight says that sometimes it’s the simple things that make the biggest difference. “Shifting your team’s focus from the grind of the negative to the fun of a positive, can work wonders for motivation and results. Help your team to smile again and your business might just smile right along with you.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;dont-bury-your-head-in-the-sand&quot;&gt;7. Don’t bury your head in the sand&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You don’t want to end up like Kodak when you could be Apple, or Blockbuster Video when you can be Netflix. If your business has indeed lost its Mojo, you need to face it, talk about it as a team and brainstorm together how to get it back fast, before your competitors swoop in with a new enthusiasm that steals your market share.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;good-news&quot;&gt;Good news&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, the good news is that if your business has lost it’s Mojo, there is still hope and there are steps you can take to get your Mojo back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re seeking inspiration, check out the new video series, &lt;a href=&quot;http://offers.businessdepot.com.au/betheexception&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;12 Reasons why successful businesses fail to implement&lt;/a&gt;, courtesy of Knight’s team at businessDEPOT. Or join a LinkedIn, Facebook or MeetUp group where you feel comfortable talking openly and/or seeking ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If, despite all your best efforts, your business cannot get its Mojo back, it might be time to sell and move on. A change can be as good as a holiday, or, in the case of a typical small business owner, a change might be the only way to get a holiday (smile).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://s-media-cache-ak0.pinimg.com/originals/b4/ef/3b/b4ef3bdeb2655f720e99db315ed23df0.jpg&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Image credit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.triggerapp.com/2017/04/has-your-business-lost-its-mojo/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.triggerapp.com/2017/04/has-your-business-lost-its-mojo/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>7 Businesses Sharing Their Metrics With The World</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Would you share your business revenue and expense metrics for all the world to see?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s not an easy thing to do. But there are businesses out there who are ignoring the general advice of “never talk about religion, politics or profits at the dinner table” and are sharing their results - awesome or ugly (granted, they’re mostly awesome) - to let others join their business journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But even for the most modern and successful company, this is still a very brave feat, because it reveals business insights and secrets that arguably might take away your competitive edge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plus, “It’s damn hard to write about what’s not working,” says Paul Towers, founder of project productivity app, &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.taskpigeon.co/three-things-struggling-founder/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Task Pigeon&lt;/a&gt;. “It makes you confront your fears, question what you are doing and figure out your next steps while sharing your story with the world.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-do-it&quot;&gt;Why do it?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.quicksprout.com/2015/01/12/how-transparency-is-the-new-marketing/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Transparency is the new marketing&lt;/a&gt;” says Neil Patel of Quicksprout (and formerly of KISSmetrics). “Being open about your business is a great way to gain people’s trust and loyalty. By sharing problems you may be facing, or by sharing your financial numbers (whether they are good or bad) will help you build a larger following. And with that following, you’ll be able to convert more of your visitors into customers.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other reasons include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Trust - the closer people feel to you, the more likely they might be to do business with you&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Accountability - who wants their metrics to go backwards after they’ve shown the world their business is going forwards?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Instant respect - whether it be Olympic medals or income reports, people admire what they cannot achieve themselves&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Opportunities - the more you put yourself out there, the more chance that new customers, partners and investors will find you&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Inspiration - if you’ve won some hard-earned battles, you may like to share your lessons learned and inspire others on their journey&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;businesses-who-share&quot;&gt;7 Businesses Who Share&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We take our hats off to seven businesses who courageously share their revenue metrics and startup journeys for us to learn from:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;hubstaff&quot;&gt;1. Hubstaff&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hubstaff co-founder Dave Nevogt tells all in &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.hubstaff.com/grow/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Hubstaff’s growth story&lt;/a&gt;, which is a must read for anyone wanting to be inspired by what’s possible when you combine business and dreams. Nevogt starts his story in June 2011, acquires 25 early adopters in November 2013, shares a big mistake they made in February 2014, and takes us through Hubstaff’s ups and downs - including full customer numbers and monthly recurring revenue (MRR) stats - all the way to January 2017, when they hit US$152,000 in MRR with 3,915 customers. Congrats Hubstaff!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/7-business-metrics/Hubstaff%20team.png&quot; alt=&quot;Hubstaff&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hubstaff offers time tracking software (similar to our time tracking and project management software at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.triggerapp.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Trigger&lt;/a&gt;) which is perfect for remote and distributed teams who collaborate on projects. And time tracking is perhaps the best example of company transparency there is, because there’s nowhere to hide when your hours and productivity is being tracked, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;buffer&quot;&gt;2. Buffer&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you run a creative agency, you’re likely already familiar with Buffer - software to help you manage and schedule social media posts for yourself and your clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Buffer walks and talks it’s value of “&lt;a href=&quot;https://buffer.com/transparency&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;default to transparency&lt;/a&gt;” like no other company we’ve seen. It shares its: equity formula and individual breakdown; company salaries (yep!); revenue; pricing; fundraising; values; books of the moment; emails (for all to read, if you work in the company); diversity; code; product roadmap; and upcoming editorial board (which allows you to see and vote on upcoming blog post ideas).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/7-business-metrics/Buffer%20transparency%201%20of%202.png&quot; alt=&quot;Buffer&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/7-business-metrics/Buffer%20transparency%201%20of%202%281%29.png&quot; alt=&quot;Buffer&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even when times got tough in June 2016 and Buffer’s CEO Joel Gascoigne had to let go 10 team members (11 percent of the company), Joel openly apologised and took full responsibility on a public blog post &lt;a href=&quot;https://open.buffer.com/layoffs-and-moving-forward/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How many other CEOs transparently own up to mistakes, versus sweep their bad news under the carpet?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;groove&quot;&gt;3. Groove&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Groove offers helpdesk software for small businesses and its founder Alex Turnbull passionately blogs about his &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.groovehq.com/blog/startup-journey&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;startup journey and revenue&lt;/a&gt;. From learning growth tactics to producing online courses, and from writing VIP email scripts to managing remote teams, Alex openly shares everything on his tell-all blog, which is Groove’s number one driver of new customers to their business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/7-business-metrics/Groove%20metrics.png&quot; alt=&quot;Groove&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;baremetrics-convertkit-and-ghost&quot;&gt;4. Baremetrics, ConvertKit and Ghost&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Baremetrics is an analytics and insights platform that shares it’s ‘live’ revenue, charges and refunds feed for all to see:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/7-business-metrics/Baremetrics%20metrics.png&quot; alt=&quot;Baremetrics&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But not only does the company cleverly use its platform to share it’s own metrics, it also makes it easy for their customers to do the same. Their &lt;a href=&quot;https://baremetrics.com/open&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Open Startups&lt;/a&gt; section shares data from companies such as ConvertKit and Ghost, who’ve opted into the transparency ride.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://convertkit.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;ConvertKit&lt;/a&gt; is a hugely successful company which offers email marketing for professional bloggers. Baremetrics reports show that ConvertKit currently makes US$627,990 MRR, which is an incredible achievement given how many email marketing products are on the market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/7-business-metrics/ConvertKit%20metrics.png&quot; alt=&quot;ConvertKit&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ghost.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Ghost&lt;/a&gt; is a non-profit organisation which offers open source, professional publishing platform. Baremetrics reports shows that Ghost currently generates an impressive US$56,686 MRR.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/7-business-metrics/Ghost%20metrics.png&quot; alt=&quot;Ghost&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;pinch-of-yum&quot;&gt;5. Pinch of Yum&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any food blogger who can bring in nearly US$100,000 MRR is already a star in my books, but sharing their exact figures, their business and personal hurdles, has to be admired.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cue Lindsay and Bjork Ostrom, food bloggers who openly share &lt;a href=&quot;http://pinchofyum.com/category/making-money-from-a-food-blog&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;their monthly income reports&lt;/a&gt; online, as well as their personal journey (including their recent pain over the death of their sweet son Afton).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/7-business-metrics/Pinch%20of%20Yum.png&quot; alt=&quot;Pinch of Yum&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;want-to-see-more&quot;&gt;Want to see more?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’d love to read more case studies, check out Anil Agarwal’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://bloggerspassion.com/bloggers-income-report-how-much-money-do-top-bloggers-make-and-how/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;BloggersPassion&lt;/a&gt; summary, where he links to Pinch of Yum bloggers Lindsay and Bjork, as well as ten more sources of income report inspiration:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/7-business-metrics/https_bloggerspassion.com_bloggers-income-report-how-much-money-do-top-bloggers-make-and-how_.png&quot; alt=&quot;BloggersPassion&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-trigger&quot;&gt;What is Trigger?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.triggerapp.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Trigger&lt;/a&gt; is a time tracking, project management and invoicing solution - perfect for creative agencies and consultancies who want to start tracking time and stop losing money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We aspire to blog transparently about our revenue and startup journey, so watch this space and we may just tell all in the near future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for visiting!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.triggerapp.com/2017/04/7-businesses-sharing-their-metrics-with-the-world/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.triggerapp.com/2017/04/7-businesses-sharing-their-metrics-with-the-world/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>7 Dilbert Videos That Prove You Need Project Management</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s Friday afternoon and your team is stressed out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Did Jan finish the artwork for the Johnson project?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“How many hours did Luca spend on content marketing this week?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Does Kim know if Amal’s client has approved more hours for this task?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s certain things that can be done every week at the last minute, but successfully managing your team’s projects is not one of them. Projects are filled with long to-do lists of important tasks that cannot be forgotten if the overall project is to be delivered stress-free, on budget and on deadline. Any successful entrepreneur will tell you that leaving project management to chance is not an option, if you want your business to scale and flourish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it’s amazing how many business owners skimp on project management tools, in order to &lt;em&gt;save&lt;/em&gt; just a few dollars a day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re a small business owner who is not convinced you need a project management system because you only have a small or medium-sized business, we’ve mustered seven &lt;a href=&quot;http://dilbert.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Dilbert&lt;/a&gt; videos by the legendary Scott Adams, to help prove why you need project management software - even when you’re just starting out and your business is small.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dilbert-the-business-plan-of-profitability&quot;&gt;1. Dilbert: The Business Plan of Profitability&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can’t know how to be profitable in the future if you don’t know what’s going on in your business right now. Without a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.triggerapp.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;good project management tool like Trigger&lt;/a&gt; to help you know the ins and outs of your business, you won’t know what’s working and what’s not working, you won’t know how to improve and you won’t be able to plan effectively to be more profitable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dilbert knows that. That’s why he delivers a ridiculous pitch to his bosses about achieving profitability in year three, when he’s had no good tools to help him put together his business plan properly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/lll_tvYWFUo&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;designed-to-fail&quot;&gt;2. Designed to Fail&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similar to writing your business plan, how can you estimate (or justify to your boss) an accurate budget for what you need for your project, if you don’t use time tracking or a project management tool to give you insights about how your business is currently performing?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One common piece of feedback we hear from our customers is that they have a tendency to be “too nice and overservice [their] clients”. This is a common mistake for agency and consultancy teams, especially when they do not have a good grasp on the budget and hours required for a project, and cannot guesstimate based on past experiences. A time tracking and project management tool can keep historical data and help you make ongoing improvements to your budgets and client quotes, based on what you’ve learned from previous projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/FMnKuZ3jVJ8&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dilbert-management-coordination&quot;&gt;3. Dilbert: Management Coordination&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coordinating managers, team members, clients, projects and tasks is difficult at the best of times. Not having a project management tool makes the process even harder and, like Dilbert, can make you want to give up before you even begin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether teams admit it or not, it’s much easier to keep everyone on the same page if they are, literally, on the same page in your project management software. A central system where tasks are assigned with clear team member accountabilities, makes life so much easier to keep things on track and to know who to follow up when things go awry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/D5MZmni7-6I&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dilbert-changes&quot;&gt;4. Dilbert: Changes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a busy world. Clients are calling you, business partners are texting you, team members are emailing you and it’s hard to keep up. By the time you come up for air of an evening to articulate new tasks, your team members have already turned off Slack and gone home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a result, you find yourself giving your team their instructions on the fly and you’re never really sure if you’ve given them everything they need. This inevitably leads to confusion later, when tasks have not been completed because team members claim you never fully briefed them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s the beauty of a project management system. Even if you don’t have time to fully articulate each task, you can log the task in your system instantly, assign it to a team member, give it a deadline. You can then ask the assignee to get more information from you (or your client) later so they can meet the deadline you set.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because ultimately, conversations are one thing, but setting deadlines assigned to specific team members is a whole other motivator. No one wants to miss a deadline and you’ll likely discover that even if the task is not articulated in full, the initiative will quickly shift to the assignee to get the details and get the task done by the deadline - which takes the burden off you to remember everything on day one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/aOC8G744MLc&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dilbert-waiting-for-the-word&quot;&gt;5. Dilbert: Waiting for the Word&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Employers don’t like seeing employees sitting around and most employees don’t like sitting around either (when they’re waiting for instructions for their next project).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re using a project management system where every single task is logged and prioritised for not just your clients but for your company’s internal to-do list (eg. everything from marketing for your own brand, to restocking the stationery cupboard), there’s never an excuse for having nothing to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Ktm0xde_p-Q&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dilbert-vicious-cycle&quot;&gt;6. Dilbert: Vicious Cycle&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Whenever I reply to email, it attracts more email. I’m trying to break the vicious cycle,” says Dilbert’s boss.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sound familiar?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Project management tools can stop the endless flurry of back-and-forth emails. They can also keep all of the conversations in one place, so when you have a team member (like Dilbert’s boss) who refuses to reply to emails, or forgets where client emails have disappeared to, everyone else on the team can easily track what’s going on and know what needs working on next.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tools like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.triggerapp.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Trigger&lt;/a&gt; can also let you invite your clients into your project management system. This enables clients to view, comment on and be tagged in discussions that inevitably save them from overwhelming and/or lost email trails as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/gc9e_6emT6c&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dilbert-only-the-things-that-matter&quot;&gt;7. Dilbert: Only the Things that Matter&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don’t use project management system with a time tracker, do you ever wonder where your hours go each day?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you ever wonder why Jane is working on social media when she should really be helping Vishnu on a more important project?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Project management tools help you prioritise tasks and focus everyone’s attention on the things that matter. If you don’t agree with how a task is prioritised on the system, you can quickly act (consult the team member assigned to the task or simply re-prioritise it on the system) before time is spent on tasks that don’t matter as much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sound good?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Ckhv4F_NcH8&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;want-more-dilbert&quot;&gt;Want more Dilbert?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you enjoyed these Dilbert videos, jump over to our second instalment, &lt;a href=&quot;/2017/05/6-dilbert-videos-that-prove-you-need-time-tracking/&quot;&gt;6 Dilbert Videos That Prove You Need Time Tracking&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re still looking for more, visit the treasure trove of Dilbert workplace videos on the Dilbert YouTube channel &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/user/dilbert/videos&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But be warned, they’re a little addictive, so watching them might not exactly help you get your projects and tasks completed on time today!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.triggerapp.com/2017/04/07-dilbert-videos-that-prove-you-need-project-management/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.triggerapp.com/2017/04/07-dilbert-videos-that-prove-you-need-project-management/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
